gardeners.com 2010-05-07

# Privacy Policy: Gardener's Supply

At Gardener’s Supply we recognize and respect the importance of maintaining your privacy and keeping your online order secure. This Privacy Policy and Security Statement describes why we gather customer and site visitor information, what information we collect, how we collect it and how we use the information as well as how we keep your order secure. This Privacy Policy and Security Statement is part of our Terms of Use, which governs your use of gardeners.com. By using gardeners.com you agree to this Privacy Policy and Security Statement and Terms of Use.  

##   
Why do we gather information?

Gardener’s Supply strives to provide our customers with quality goods and excellent customer service. We gather information to allow us to process orders, to enhance and personalize our customers’ shopping experience and to inform our customers and e-mail subscribers of special offers and discounts.  

## What information do we gather?

When you order from gardeners.com, we collect the following information: your name, telephone number, e-mail address, billing information (credit card number, expiration date and billing address), products purchased, any relevant promotion code and information (gift certificate redemption code, for example) and, if relevant, the recipient's name, address and telephone number. Information you enter is collected even if you cancel or do not complete an order. 

## How do we use "cookies"?

A "cookie" is a small data file stored on your computer by our web site that gives you a numeric user ID and stores certain information about your activity on the site. We use cookies to let us know if you are a previous customer and also to provide certain features to you, such as storing items in your shopping basket as you shop on our site. 

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, and most also allow you to instruct your browser to prevent the use of cookies. However, if you disable this feature certain aspects of gardeners.com, such as the shopping basket, will not function properly. 

If you prefer not to allow your browser to accept cookies, you can place your order by telephone at 1-888-833-1412. Another option for placing your order is to print out your shopping basket and fax or mail it along with your shipping and billing address and credit card information to us. Mail or fax to: 

Gardener’s Supply Company  
128 Intervale Rd.  
Burlington, VT 05401  
Attn: Data Entry  
Fax. 1-800-551-6712

##   
Third Party Cookies

Gardener's Supply Company has contracted with Demandware Inc. ("Demandware"), to track and analyze website usage and volume satistical information from our visitors and customers. All data collected on our behalf is owned and used soley by us to administer and constantly improve the quality of our website. To accomplish this, Demandware uses cookie technology to help track summarized visitor behavior. 

##   
How do we use the information we collect about you?

We use information we collect from you to process your orders, to provide an enhanced and more personalized shopping experience and to inform you of offers and discounts from Gardener’s Supply. Gardener's Supply shares its customer information with its vendor partners and with members of the America's Gardening Resource (AGR) family of wholly-owned affiliates, including Flower Power Fundraising. When you subscribe to Gardener's Supply e-mail, you may also receive occasional e-mails from other members of the AGR family of wholly-owned affiliates. In addition, we periodically make such information, including aggregated information, available to selected third parties.

Gardener’s Supply uses an e-mail service provider to send targeted promotional e-mails and our Gardener’s News e-mail newsletter to our subscriber list. We share with our provider usage information about visitors to our site who have received these e-mails. This service provider does not sell this information. This information is used to help deliver and target future e-mail campaigns and upgrade visitor information used in reporting statistics. To collect usage information, we note some of the pages you visit on our web site through pixel tags (also called clear gifs). The information collected through the use of these pixel tags is personally identifiable. For more information about our third-party advertising company, please [click here](http://www.doubleclick.com/us/corporate/privacy/privacy/email/default.asp?asp_object_1=&). If you would like to be removed from our e-mail list, please follow the instructions at the bottom of each promotional e-mail, or just [e-mail us](http://www.gardeners.com/on/demandware.store/Sites-Gardeners-Site/default/Link-Contactus?a=b) with your request. 

Gardener’s Supply Company does not sell, trade or rent your e-mail address. We occasionally send offers to our customers on behalf of other trusted businesses, but we do not give those businesses your personal information. 

In the event of a merger, consolidation, or sale or transfer of all or substantially all of the assets or business of Gardener’s Supply (a "Successor"), one of the assets which would generally be transferred is the information we collect from our customers and site visitors. However, the use of this information by any Successor would still be governed by the terms of this privacy policy, as amended from time to time, including any amendment after such transaction. 

We may disclose any information you provide to Gardener’s Supply when we believe disclosure to be appropriate to comply with any law, regulation, or governmental request, or to comply with judicial process; or (ii) if such disclosure is necessary or appropriate to operate this web site; or (iii) to protect the rights or property of Gardener’s Supply Company, its users, Sponsors, Providers, Licensors, or Merchants. 

## Links

Gardener’s Supply wants you to be aware that when you click on links and/or ad banners that take you to third-party Web sites, you will be subject to the third parties' privacy policies, not ours. While we support the protection of privacy on the Internet, we cannot be responsible for the actions of third parties. We encourage you to read the posted privacy statement and user terms and conditions whenever interacting with, and prior to providing any personal information to, any other website. 

## Your Security

We understand that the safety of your personal information is extremely important to you. We take great care in protecting your privacy and ensuring a safe online shopping experience at www.gardeners.com. Our site uses Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption technology to ensure the secure transmission of any personal information you provide while using our website. We also comply with Payment Card indsutry requirements and our site is regularly scanned and validated by Trustwave. 

The Fair Credit Act specifies that your credit card company can hold you liable for no more that $50 in fraudulent charges to your account. If you feel you've incurred a fraudulent charge with us or any retailer, promptly notify your credit card company and follow the procedures outlined in your credit card agreement. 

## Your Consent and Changes to this Policy

Subject to the above provisions, by using our web site, you consent to the collection and use of information by us and the terms of this Privacy Policy. We may change our Privacy Policy from time to time and we will post those changes 30 days prior to their taking effect so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we may disclose it.

##   
Your Comments

We welcome feedback concerning this Privacy Policy and Security Statement. To send your comments and questions just [e-mail us](http://www.gardeners.com/on/demandware.store/Sites-Gardeners-Site/default/Link-Contactus?a=b).
